# Ajay Rajput

### Certified SAFe® 5 Agilest, PMPO, CSPO®, DevOps Engineer, Platform Engineer

With a background in embedded systems engineering, eager to transition skills and experience to a career in DevOps. With over nine years of hands-on experience developing, testing, and deploying embedded software systems and a solid understanding of software development life cycles and methodologies. Implemented automation processes using AWS, Azure, Terraform, Docker, and Kubernetes, resulting in a 40% reduction in manual efforts and a 20% increase in deployment speed.

iamapsrajput@outlook.com

+48-517115282

Wrocław, Poland

linkedin.com/in/iamapsrajput

### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Adaptability & Flexibility

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Cloud Platforms:** AWS, Azure, Google Cloud **Automation Tools:** 

Terraform, Jenkins, Ansible

Containerisation

Docker, Kubernetes

Methodologies:

Scrum, Agile, V-Model, Waterfall Model

**Technologies:** 

DO-178B/C, EN-50128, MISRA

**Programming** 

C, C++, Python

**Standards Guidelines:** 

Languages:

**Embedded Testing Tools:** 

LDRA, Vector Cast, RT Tester

**Designing IDs:** 

Eclipse, Understand C++, VS Code

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **DevOps / Lead Engineer**

Raytheon Technologies (Former Collins Aerospace)

10/2016 - 10/2022

Bengaluru, India / Cedar Rapids, USA

#### Responsibilities

- Implemented and maintained continuous integration and delivery continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) pipelines
- Accountable for overseeing the source code repository, organized structure, and robust security
- Build, tested, and deployed applications in environments, such as development, testing, and production
- Automated infrastructure deployment and ensured repeatable and consistent across different environments
- Led a group of engineers in an Agile process that includes daily stand-ups, presentations to higher management, reviews of code development, and testing (White Box, Black Box, Integration, and System testing)
- Presented a concept for a tracker system aimed at enhancing process efficiency, and productivity, capturing lessons learned, facilitating selfreviews, and streamlining reviewer checklists
- Facilitated Agile ceremonies, including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, retrospectives, and demos, for team alignment and effective communication

#### Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

11/2015 - 09/2016

Bengaluru, India

#### Responsibilities

- Reviewed models and C Code according to high-level requirements; performed code reviews and bug
- Led five team members to deliver quality, error-free interactive products to the customers
- Executed test script on Target and Simulated environment and validate results
- Developed design concerning SDD standards shared by Client and verification of SDD, authored by another person for different system
- Guided in the creation of Test plans, Test suites, Test scenarios & Test data for white box testing
- Performed SWI using LDRA and HSI testing using RT tester tool, respectively, which involved writing and executing TPs

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Software Engineer**

CYIENT Ltd

01/2013 - 07/2014

Responsibilities

Bengaluru, India

- Performed system and subsystem testing, including functional, performance, and unit testing
- Developed and implemented test plans, test cases, and procedures for verifying and validating avionics systems
- Preparation and documentation of test scenarios, test cases, test data, and test automation approach
- O Reviewed top-level requirements and interface documents provided by the client
- Developed SRD from top-level requirements and interface document concerning SRD standards provided by client
- Daily interaction with Client, demonstrating failure found and after thorough analysis, raised Problem Reports
- Performed hardware and software integration testing for Load-Master Work Station Applications
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure product quality and compliance with industry standards and regulations

#### **Programmer**

IAP Company Pvt Ltd

01/2012 - 12/2013

Responsibilities

Gurugram, India

- O Joined a team of 14 people and collaborated with the development team to upgrade the current system for improvements
- Risk assessments and developed mitigation strategies for improving the SDD requirements
- Developed automated test procedures in C and python language based on test cases requirement
- O Developed Test Cases and Test Procedures from Low-Level Software Design Document
- O Documented and reported test results, issues, and recommendations for improvement

### **CERTIFICATES**

Certified SAFe® 5 Agilest (04/2022 - Present)

Certified SAFe® 5 Product Owner/Product Manager (03/2022 - Present)

Product Masterclass: How to Build Digital Products (06/2021 - Present)

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) (04/2022 - Present)

Learn DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, and Azure DevOps (01/2023 - Present)

Agile Product Owner Role: Techniques (06/2021 - Present)

### **EDUCATION**

# Post Graduate Degree, Al and Machine Learning

**Purdue University** 

11/2022 Purdue University Online

## MBA (Information Technology)

Sikkim Manipal University

06/2017 Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

# B.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering)

**Uttar Pradesh Technical University** 

06/2011 Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India

# Diploma (Computer Science and Engineering)

Board of Technical Education, Lucknow

06/2008 Unnao, Uttar Pradesh, India

# AWARDS

Star Award (Twice)
Raytheon Technologies

PAT on the Back
Raytheon Technologies

#### QUADRANT Award

Raytheon Technologies

Team of the Month

Tata Consultancy Services

### LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Elementary Proficiency